Preliminary Guide to the American Economic Association Records, 1886-2008 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Accession (2001-0082)
  - AER Acceptances, 1999 December (Box 15-16)
- Accession (2002-0215)
  Addition (2002-0215) (21000 items, 33.4 linear feet; dated 1999-2001) contains Records for the American Economic Review, including editorial correspondence, referee reports, and manuscripts for rejected articles (1999-2000) and accepted articles (March-December 2001) and papers and proceedings (2000-2001). There are also 37 electronic documents on one floppy disk. The electronic documents have been transferred to the electronic records server.
  - AER Rejects, A-B, 1999 (Box 1)
  - AER Rejects, B-C, 1999 (Box 2)
  - AER Rejects, C-F, 1999 (Box 3)
  - AER Rejects, G-H, 1999 (Box 4)
  - AER Rejects, H-K, 1999 (Box 5)
  - AER Rejects, K-M, 1999 (Box 6)
  - AER Rejects, M-O, 1999 (Box 7)
  - AER Rejects, O-R, 1999 (Box 8)
  - AER Rejects, R-S, 1999 (Box 9)
  - AER Rejects, S-W, 1999 (Box 10)
  - AER Rejects, W-Z, 1999 (Box 11)
  - AER Rejects, A, 2000
  - AER Rejects, A, 2000 (Box 12)
  - AER Rejects, A-B, 2000 (Box 13)
  - AER Rejects, B, 2000 (Box 14)
  - AER Rejects, B-C, 2000 (Box 15)
  - AER Rejects, C, 2000 (Box 16-17)
  - AER Rejects, C-D, 2000 (Box 18)
  - AER Rejects, D-E, 2000 (Box 19)
  - AER Rejects, E-F, 2000 (Box 20)
  - AER Rejects, F-G, 2000 (Box 21)
  - AER Rejects, G, 2000 (Box 22)
  - AER Rejects, G-H, 2000 (Box 23)
  - AER Rejects, H, 2000 (Box 24)
  - AER Rejects, H-I, 2000 (Box 25)
  - AER Rejects, I-K, 2000 (Box 26)
  - AER Rejects, K, 2000 (Box 27)
  - AER Rejects, K-L, 2000 (Box 28)
  - AER Rejects, L, 2000 (Box 29)
  - AER Rejects, L-M, 2000 (Box 30)
  - AER Rejects, M, 2000 (Box 31)
  - AER Rejects, M-N, 2000 (Box 32)
  - AER Rejects, N-P, 2000 (Box 33)
  - AER Rejects, P, 2000 (Box 34)
  - AER Rejects, P-R, 2000 (Box 35)
  - AER Rejects, R-S, 2000 (Box 36)
  - AER Rejects, S, 2000 (Box 37-39)
  - AER Rejects, S-T, 2000 (Box 40)
  - AER Rejects, T-W, 2000 (Box 41)
  - AER Rejects, W, 2000 (Box 42)
  - AER Rejects, W-Z, 2000 (Box 43)
  - AER Rejects, Z, 2000 (Box 44)
  - AER Acceptances, 2000 March
  - AER Acceptances, 2000 June
  - AER Acceptances, 2000 September
  - AER Acceptances, 2000 March (cont.) (Box 45)
  - AER Acceptances, 2000 June (cont.)
  - AER Acceptances, 2000 September (cont.)
  - AER Acceptances, 2000 March (cont.) (Box 46)
  - AER Acceptances, 2000 June (cont.)
  - AER Acceptances, 2000 September (cont.)
  - AER Acceptances, 2000 March (cont.) (Box 47)
  - AER Acceptances, 2000 June (cont.)
  - AER Acceptances, 2000 September (cont.)
  - AER Acceptances, 2000 December
  - AER Acceptances, 2001 March
  - AER Acceptances, 2000 December (cont.) (Box 48)
  - AER Acceptances, 2001 March (cont.)
  - AER Acceptances, 2000 December (cont.) (Box 49)
  - AER Acceptances, 2001 March (cont.)
  - AER Acceptances, 2001 June
  - AER Acceptances, 2001 September
  - AER Acceptances, 2001 December
  - AER Acceptances, 2001 June (Box 50-52)
  - AER Acceptances, 2001 September
  - AER Acceptances, 2001 December
  - Papers and Proceedings, 2000 (Box 53)
  - Papers and Proceedings, 2000 (cont.) (Box 54)
  - Papers and Proceedings, 2001 (Box 55)
  - Papers and Proceedings, 2001 (cont.) (Box 56)
- Accession (2003-0250), 42 Boxes
  Addition (2003-0250) (15750 items, 25.2 lin. ft.; dated 1996-2002) is closed to researchers. Collection contains records for the American Economic Review, including editorial correspondence, referee reports, and manuscripts for rejected articles (primarily 2001 and 2002) and accepted articles (2002).
  Written permission from the American Economics Association is required for 50 years. Please see Research Services with questions.
- Accession (2004-0007), 18 Boxes
  Addition (2004-0007) (5250 items, 10.8 lin. ft.; dated 1950-2002) consists of general and committee files from the AEA administrative office; Elton Hinshaw's files as the association's secretary-treasurer (ca. 1983-late 1990s); printed programs for annual meetings (1950-2001); agendas and supporting documents for executive committee meetings (ca. 1992-1997); and a 2002 membership directory (in print and on CD-Rom). Also includes files on the Committee on Graduate Education (ca. 1988-1991) and the Committee on the Status of Minority Groups (ca. 1986-2001).
- Accession (2004-0039), 11 Boxes
  Addition (2004-0039) (4125 items; 6.6 lin. ft.; dated 2001) consists of files of rejected articles (2001) from the American Economic Review, including correspondence, referee reports, and manuscripts.
- Accession (2004-0092), 8 Boxes
  Addition (2004-0092) (3000 items; 4.8 lin. ft.; dated 2001-2003) contains files for accepted articles for 2003 issues of the American Economic Review, including the May 2003 Papers and Proceedings. Files contain typescripts of articles, correspondence, and referees' reports.
- Accession (2004-0132), 1 Box
  Addition (2004-0132) (3 items, 0.4 lin. ft.; dated 2003) consists of a printed copy (3 vols.) of the 2003 AEA membership directory.
- Accession (2004-0316), 57 Boxes
  Addition (2004-0316) (21375 items; 34.2 lin. ft.; dated 1993-2004) consists of journal records for the American Economic Review, 1993-2004, including correspondence and referee files for rejected and withdrawn articles, accepted articles, and papers and proceedings.
- Accession (2005-0069), 0 Boxes
  Addition (2005-0069) (5 items; .1 lin. ft.; dated 2004-2005) comprises a CD-R containing five electronic files for the 2004 membership directory (3 electronic files saved in different formats). Copies of the electronic documents have been transferred to the electronic records server.
- Accession (2006-0053), 10 Boxes
  Addition (2006-0053) (3,750 items, 6 lin. ft.; dated 1980-2000) includes records of the AEA Committee on the Status of Women in the Economics Profession (CSWEP), primarily 1996-2000, including correspondence of the chair, annual reports, minutes of the Board, rosters, and files relating to CSWEP newsletters and program sessions at AEA meetings.
- Accession (2006-0066), 60 Boxes
  Addition (2006-0066) (22,025 items, 35.6 lin. ft.; dated 1962-1966, 1995-2005) features records for the American Economic Review, including correspondence and referee reports regarding papers rejected for publication, primarily 2001-2004. Also includes Local Arrangements Reports for conventions of the Allied Social Science Association, 1962-1966.
- Accession (2007-0084 and 2007-0085), 17 Boxes
  Additions (2007-0084 and 2007-0085) (7500 items, 10.0 lin. ft.; dated 2004-2006) contain records for the American Economic Review, including drafts, correspondence, and referee reports for articles dated 2004-2006. Also included is the AEA member directory for 2006.
- Accession (2007-0089 and 2007-0090), 90 Boxes
  Additions (2007-0089 and 2007-0090) (2500 items, 3.4 lin. ft.; dated 1994-2003) contain records for the Journal of Economic Literature, and primarily includes referee reports and correspondence related to accepted articles dated 1994-2003.
- Accession (2008-0066), 1 Box
  Addition (08-066) (8 items, .6 lin. ft.; dated 2006-2007) comprises membership directories for those years. Includes two CDR's.
- Accession (2008-0239), 6 Boxes
  Addition (2008-0239) (2250 items; 3.6 lin. ft.; dated 2008) contains records for the American Economic Review, including drafts, correspondence, and referee reports for articles submitted for publication for vol. 98, issues 1-4 (March-Sept. 2008).
- Accession (2008-0269), 2 Boxes
  Addition (2008-0269) (1575 items; 2.1 lin. ft.; dated 2005) contains records for the Journal of Economic Literature, including referee reports and drafts of accepted articles for issues in 2005.
  - Journal of Economic Literature, June 2005 (Box 1)
  - Journal of Economic Literature, March 2005
  - Journal of Economic Literature, September 2005
  - Journal of Economic Literature, September 2005 (Box 2)
  - Journal of Economic Literature, December 2005
- Accession (2009-0204), (7 boxes)
  Addition (09-204) (7875 items; 10.5 lin. ft.; dated 2006-2008) includes files for the American Economic Review, volumes 96(2), 97(2), 97(4), 97(5), 98(2) and 98(5).
  - American Economic Review Papers and Proceedings, Vol. 96(2), May 2006 (Box 1-2)
  - American Economic Review Papers and Proceedings, Vol. 97(2), May 2007 (Box 3)
  - American Economic Review, Vol. 97(4), September 2007 (Box 4)
  - American Economic Review, Vol. 97(5), December 2007 (Box 5)
  - American Economic Review Papers and Proceedings, Vol. 98(2), May 2008 (Box 6)
  - American Economic Review, Vol. 98(5), December 2008 (Box 7)
- Accession (2011-0083), (4 boxes)
  Addition (2011-0083) (3525 items; 4.7 lin. ft.; dated 2005-2006) contains files for the Journal of Economic Perspectives, including unsolicited papers and proposals; e-mail correspondence; and article drafts and revisions. Not all unsolicited papers and proposals received by the JEP during these years are included; only those of some interest have been saved (for instance, if the author of the paper was particularly notable.) The bulk of the material consists of articles and proposals from 2005 and 2006, the last years before the JEP began publishing and archiving electronically. A few folders pertain to articles published after 2006. These are articles that were began before the JEP's switch to electronic, and thus some of their early files are archived on paper rather than electronically.
  - Journal of Economic Perspectives Proposal List 2005, (57 folders) (Box 1)
  - Journal of Economic Perspectives Proposal List 2006, (20 folders)
  - Journal of Economic Perspectives drafts and revisions of articles published in the Spring 2005 issue, (8 folders)
  - Journal of Economic Perspectives drafts and revisions of articles published in the Summer 2005 issue, (32 folders) (Box 1-2)
  - Journal of Economic Perspectives drafts and revisions of articles published in the Winter 2005 issue, (27 folders) (Box 2-3)
  - Journal of Economic Perspectives drafts and revisions of articles published in the Spring 2006 issue, (15 folders) (Box 3)
  - Journal of Economic Perspectives drafts and revisions of articles published in the Summer 2006 issue, (14 folders)
  - Journal of Economic Perspectives drafts and revisions of articles published in the Fall 2006 issue, (12 folders)
  - Journal of Economic Perspectives drafts and revisions of articles published in the Winter 2007 issue, (12 folders)
  - Journal of Economic Perspectives drafts and revisions of articles published in the Spring 2007 issue, (5 folders)
  - Journal of Economic Perspectives drafts and revisions of articles published in the Summer 2007 issue, (11 folders)
  - Journal of Economic Perspectives drafts and revisions of articles published in the Fall 2007 issue, (3 folders)
  - Journal of Economic Perspectives drafts and revisions of articles published in the Winter 2008 issue, (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Journal of Economic Perspectives drafts and revisions of articles published in the Spring 2008 issue, (3 folders)
  - Journal of Economic Perspectives drafts and revisions of articles published in the Summer 2008 issue, (1 folder)
  - Journal of Economic Perspectives drafts and revisions of articles published in the Winter 2009 issue, (1 folder)
- Accession (2012-0077), 1995-1998, (3 boxes)
  Addition (2012-0077) (4.5 lin. ft.; 3375 items; dated 1995-1998) contains files from the Journal of Economic Literature during the editorship of John Pencavel.
  - JEL files, 1995-1998 (Box 1-3)